hey guys sh side welcome to concept and
coding and today in springboard I will
be covering the second level cashing
very very important very frequently used
in the big mnc's also it's not just like
it's a concept it's used actually in
production level codes also so before I
start this is the prerequisite like if
you know the architecture of jpa and the
first level of cash but those who
haven't seen the first level of cash I
will just give in couple of minutes give
the quick overview of the first level
caching so in the first level caching
you already know that these are the
basic setup like we have created One
controller where we have post mapping
get mapping we have a service class
which talks to the repository in
repository we have extend the jpa
repository you already know in depth
like uh why what's the API what all the
method it support and and here if you
see that this is one entity which we
have created okay now in if you can
recall from the uh first level of
caching whenever you make a new request
a new entity manager object get created
and for each entity manager object uh
one persistence context which is helpful
in the first level of caching is
happened so that's what I'm doing here
when I'm making a first HTTP request
insert call okay
so we see a
insert query executed properly now when
I make a second call get call what
happened here if you see another select
query happened okay now here if you see
I make another get call another get call
means another new request new request
means new entity manager object okay so
here in this case you see another select
query so there is no first level caching
is applied here means there is no cash
hit happening why because whenever any
new call happen a new entity manager
object is get created and for each
entity manager object we have a
different persistence
context okay so that's why you are not
able to see any cash hit between here
even though it's the same two times I'm
doing a get call okay so every time I
make a new request new object is created
and it has its own persistent context it
is not aware of this one where this uh
uh object is present okay so it's not
aware of this it is only aware of its
persistent context since it is not there
it hit the DB it make a new select query
okay
but if if you're using the same get call
and same entity manager if you doing
first get and then second time get then
the first time get it make a DB call it
put the object here the second time this
object same persistence object is used
so it would be cash hit same entity
manager object means same persistence
context object would be used and the
second time since the object is present
cash it would
happen Okay and and with every HTTP
request new entity manager object was
created and that was the
reason why we are seeing this
Behavior okay so this is all about the
first level caching I have explained it
in depth if you find this little bit in
hurry first level caching because we
have already covered in depth in the
previous video now since we have
recalled a bid now let's move to the
second level caching which is L2 caching
also many time in IND
you will hear Engineers are saying hey
what about the L2 caching what data is
there in L2 caching second level caching
is known as L2 caching and what
generally happen in this is
here so
till between this persistence context
and DB now there is one more layer comes
which is your second level caching so
whenever any call
comes okay entity manager object is
created it has has its own persistence
context now before it looks for DB it
again another layer so you consider this
L1 and this is as L2 so now it checks
second level caching hey that data is
present here or not data is present here
or not so even though you are hitting
multiple requests different requests
different objects different persistence
context but they are sharing a same
second level caching now
so even for this there is a chance that
we are increasing the chance that the
cashit will increase because this is
also in memory so this is also fast but
only difference is it is shared among
different persistence
context okay and then ultimately goes to
the DB and whatever the data comes from
DB it go first go you can say that goes
to L2 cach and then L1 cach and then out
okay so let's see one happy flow and see
what all it takes to enable the second
level caching if I want to enable it how
we can do
it so first thing we have to add the
dependencies so we have to add this
three
dependencies okay eh
cach
hibernate jcash and jxc API okay you can
check out the latest version which is
applicable for springbot 3.x version
which we are using so you can check out
the latest version of this which is uh
applicable for this spring boot version
and we can use it but this three
dependency we needed why we need that I
will tell you but I am just telling you
very quick overview we'll go one by one
each and we'll tell you but first thing
is we required
form in application. properties we have
to enable certain
configurations like second level caching
true like we are enable the cach um
second level casing but don't worry
about this so this is the second changes
we need first you have added dependency
second in application. properties we
have enabled some
configuration here in the service layer
no change right it is the basic like
your repository you are just calling the
repository nothing no change then you
have repository no change
okay then after that you
have your
entity so in the entity you will see
this
part at theate cache okay so we it we
are just telling the hibernate that do a
second level caching for this
entity okay whenever this request comes
for this ENT entity or whenever anybody
is working on this entity before
touching to DB first check in
L2 L2
cach okay we will see that what does it
mean region and all and here if you
see again don't worry about this what's
the purpose of each one we will go one
by one each but here if you see pal
application. properties and this three
no change fourth no change how we were
using only fifth is like you have to put
at the rate cache which is like we are
telling hiet that we have to put a
second level cach on this entity user
details that's all now here if you see
first step I am doing an insert data is
directly inserted into DB no cash
insertion or validation happens so I am
calling a post
operation and data is inserted so first
happen second
do I am making a one get
call okay whatever the data is inserted
I am doing a get call since this is the
first get call Cash Miss will happen and
DB call will be made so what would be
the
sequences
get entity manager it will check its
persistence context it will check second
level caching and then check DB so data
is present into persistence contact no
data is present in L2 caching no because
during insert also no data is inserted
into uh L2 so it will hit a DB and
then it will put into L2 put into L1 and
then ultimately goes
out
okay so this is the second call where if
you see that cash Miss happen and it
make a DB call and then it will also
cashing data from load so it will also
load the
data now the third time I am making a
get call now this
time data is present into L2 it don't
have to goes into the DB itself okay
okay so this is a
new get
call means new get call
means new entity manager object and
since it's a new entity manager object
new persistence context so data was
present into this one but this is a new
request so new persistent context so
there is no uh hit from the first L1 but
L2 is same for multiple persistence
context now it will check L2 data is
present into L2 right from the previous
call so it would be cash hit and no DB
hit
required so here if you see cash hit
happened during the
second okay so this is very
one functional flow for the second level
caching now let's see why and what all
things are required what is the purpose
for
that so in pom.xml I told you that we
need three
dependencies okay so here if you see
first one is or. ehcache and the version
provide the core implementation of
second level caching so here if you see
right there are multiple cach eh cach
caffeine cash hle cost okay so
which provider you want to use for the
second level cashing okay we want to use
one I am going with the eh cash you can
also go with the caffeine cash doesn't
matter okay because we don't have to go
inside the working of this why I'll tell
you now because of this second so this
was first and now this is let's say
second what is this cash hun API so this
this is like a
interface okay it expose all the API
let's say get
cash I'm just saying that uh create
cach okay and they provide the
implementation for it so we are only
interested in invoking the
API okay and this apis are the
interfaces which are implemented by this
second level cash providers okay so
that's why we have to bring this
dependency also with which says that
this is the interface which your
hibernate code can interact with so that
in future if you change from eh Cas to
caffeine your code will not impact at
all because you are dealing with the
interface who is the provider it can
change okay so this is to bring this
jcash API interfaces this dependency is
required now this is the third which is
required so this is our hibernate code
now this hnet has to talk to this jcash
API and there are many annotations like
at the rate cash like there are like at
the rate uh like
concurrency strategy cash concurrency
strategy there are so many specific
annotation and variable fields we are
going to use for caching so those are
understand by hibernate jcash so you can
consider as a bridge
bridge between hibernate and the jcash
interface apis right so it provide a
bridge that okay whatever The annotation
you are adding specifically for caching
this understands it and I hnet knows how
to talk with hnet jash okay so that's
why the name hibernate hyund jcash so
consider as a bridge between hibernate
and jcash hibernate can't directly knows
that when to create uh create cash when
to call get cash when to call put cash
no but this knows so you can consider as
an as an orchestrator like based on the
value which you are using during cashing
let's say I am using read WR I am using
read only what method to call what
validations to add it can have it okay
so considered as a bridge between
hibernate and cash which understand how
to talk with the
jcash
apis okay so these three are required so
no matter
what you need cash API you need
hibernate but here you can instead you
can use ecash or you can use caffeine or
hle cast whichever you want based upon
your need you can change
it so first thing is clear right why
this three dependency in pom.xml
required now let's understand the
application.
properties so this is the first
configuration we have to unable by
default second level cach is false okay
so we have to unable it to True okay
once we unable it then only second level
cash is start functioning then only like
it will all these things comes into the
picture otherwise
no the second is your
region region Factory class but before
understanding the region Factory class
we need to First understand what is
region okay so let me tell you in short
like what is region then I'll tell you
why we need to set the factory
class so region helps in logical
grouping of cache data logical
grouping for each region we can apply
different catching strategy like what is
the eviction policy like Leo fif lru
whatever okay uh last in first out first
in first out least recently used so
whatever the eviction policy you want to
use you can apply to different uh region
wise time to live for the cash data what
is the cash size like how many entries
you can store in a cash like 1,00 100
200 and what is the concurrency strategy
okay so here if you see an example this
is one entity user details and this is
I'm creating another entity or
detail okay now here if you see I am
enabling at the rate cach annotation so
now you know that at the rate cash this
is some cash specific uh annotation
which is aware of aware by hibernate
jash it knows what to do and we have
also enabled second level caching so it
comes into the
picture now here if you see that what
region we have G given is user detail
cache so consider that one region is us
user detail cache and for order what
reason I have given is order detail
cache order detail cache okay so here it
uh stores this entity user details user
details entity it takes care of order
details entity multiple entities it can
group like which I want to group inside
this region and multiple entities which
I group want to group inside this region
we can give any name of the region
now here if you
see either in application do Properties
or generally I feel comfortable with EH
c. XML like a specific file which we can
put in Source main resources and provide
this
configuration okay for this cat alash
user detail cach means this this region
okay this region what is the in memory
how many how many entries you want to
put what is the TTL for the data which
is stored what is the eviction strategy
you want to use so no matter how many
entities you are grouping
together all this uh strategy like
eviction TTL and uh
your
memory would be applicable for this but
maybe possible that for the order one
you want different you don't want the
same so here I I have TTL for 60 seconds
here you want a TTL for 500 seconds
let's say okay so that's why it's a
logical grouping for each region you can
provide this one so for order you can
give time to live is 200 seconds I want
1,000 uh entries for this one and the
strategy is
F4 so region provide you more granual
way you can manage your
cash okay and the second property says
that region Factory class who is going
to manage that jcash region Factory so
now here if you see that this hibernate
cache also has Factory
class okay and also this eh cach also
has a factory
class if you want to directly work with
this like hey you take care
of managing all the cash directly then
you can directly use eh cash
but I would always say that it's better
that if you use hiet jcash because in
future if you change from eh Cas to
caffeine you don't have to change lot of
codes because this all work with
interfaces beneath the provider can
change over the
time okay so here I have used jcash
region Factory this one which is present
by hibern
jcash so this manage everything like
insertion like get cash create cash it
manages the region proper region so for
this region what is the TTL what is the
catch eviction policy so it will take
care of it but if you want to use
directly you can use directly eh Cas
also but that again it comes with like
benefit is there you don't have like
abstraction you are directly working but
you know the disadvantage also right if
future you have to change you might have
to change the code also a lot
okay
so you can Define the factory class
which will take care of your management
of the cash data
Okay the third one is the provider like
ehh caching provider so even though we
have added the dependency but this like
you have added the cash we need to tell
the spring boot that which provider I am
using just by adding the dependency in
pal uh in this case hibernate jcash
doesn't know which provider it has to
use so we have to set this configuration
that hey I want to use eh Cas caching
provider so that whenever it calls get
cash it creates an object for this one
and it invokes eh cach so similarly you
can uh add differently if you are
working with different cash
provider okay so these three are
important this is just for debug so that
whenever we hit a query uh we will some
something at print out if insert query
select query so that we can see but this
three only is application. property is
important okay now let's say different
cash concurrency
strategy now here if you see if you have
focused on the
entity object we have put at theate cach
at the cash is like uh hibernate hyphen
uh jcash knows that this is used for
second level caching and we have to cach
this entity okay in the L2 cache but
there is something called usage equals
to catch concurrency strategy there are
four types of concurrency strategy read
only read write nonstrict read write
transactional so which one you want to
use depends upon business to
business so I'll tell you what is this
cash concurrency strategy
is read only let's go with the first
read only but in short if I give you a
definition of cat concurrency strategy I
would say that uh this will guide how
your operation insert update delete
impact your cash
data okay so so that they can work in
parallel without uh you can say that
it's possible that in in some business
use case stale data is possible so you
select a prop proper strategy in some
business scenario stale data is not even
applicable it should not have happened
then we have to pick up appropriate
strategy so concurrency strategy is like
how you maintain handle the concurrent
request like get update delete is coming
and you have the data in the cache and
the DB how you want to handle
it so let's go ahead with the first one
read
only good for static
data data which do not require any
updates any updates not even I'm saying
less update any update if you try to
update an entity exception will come so
see this like here in the request
controller I have put another put
mapping just to make sure that I will
also update some data this is service
where I am updating
with the existing ID I'm first fetching
the data and then I'm saving it so it
will try to update it repository and
here ultimately entity The Entity I'm
using read
only now first let's say I have done
insert okay insert directly put the data
into DB user detail let's say then I am
doing get when you are do a get first
cach Miss will happen then it will hit
DB and then it will put the data
into L2 cach also so user detail let's
say one here user detain one here this
is your L2 cach and this is your
DB now I'm trying to do a put call I am
trying to do a put call but here I have
put read only this entity user detail
entity is read only so
now when I call a put request what I got
internal error what says that you can't
update read only
object
okay so here if you see who has this
logic hibernate uh this one 6.5.2 like
hibernate Jas knows
that understand this cash concurrency
strategies this one
okay then we have a read write now there
are use cases where you have a scenario
where multiple reads update delete can
happen in parallel and you want to
manage those so this might be applicable
and also it's a scenario like where you
don't want stale data to be return also
so this is better in that case let's say
during read it put a shared
log so other read can also acquire
shared log but no right operation so now
let's say that you have L2 cach you have
DB you have user detail one here user
detail one here now get call one is
happening get call two is happening it
put a log internally on the cach but it
is not blocking other get calls also so
read call can happen multiple read call
so they can do a cashit multiple cashit
can happen nobody is stopping
anybody but it will not allow any right
operation but any right operation comes
let's say put it will stop it okay
because still the lock is present read
call and during update it put kind of a
exclusive log where read and write
operation are not
allowed so
here if you see that whenever any update
happen What happen is understand this
scenario what happen is how it handles
this this one is simple whenever you do
a insert directly goes to the DB cash
not even comes into the picture L2 cash
only comes into the picture once we do a
first get
call okay then you do a get call L2 cach
comes into the picture cash Miss happen
goes to the DB then it load into the L2
cach and then kind of uh return it if
there is a cash it happen directly
return from here no need to go to the
DB now let's say update is happening
what it does so now let's say you have a
data into L2 cach you have a data into
DB one put call update call is happening
you have entity one here entity one here
how it will make sure that how it will
update it how it will make sure that
any get is happening in
parallel it do not read the scale data
so as you know that any update let's say
transaction
begins first it will do is acquire lock
on cach it prevent stale data read from
cash no read and write aloud after that
so once it has taken the lock acquired a
lock on this
entity what it will do it will make it
invalidate so there is a flag here
inside this cach data
it make it
invalidate okay after that it will
update its DB whatever the update
required let's say E1 is changed to E1
hash
something if it commit
properly okay then it will update the
cache data with the latest data and
remove the invalidate so now while
returning it will update the cach here
in the L2 also E1 hash and remove the
invalidate flag now this is also valid
and then it will release the lock on the
cash now it will release the lock on the
cash but if there is any roll back
happen if there is any roll back happen
what it will do is it will just release
the lock on cash it won't remove the
invalidate
flag okay so now let's say that L2 cash
it was entity
One DB
entity one during put call it put make
it
invalidate and while processing some
issue happens and it roll back
transaction got roll
back so it it just removed the lock so
it put a lock right it acquired the lock
it will just release the lock on the
cach but it will not remove this
invalidate flag and no updation will
happen so now in future any get call
will come as since the lock is released
any get call will come it will see that
hey it is marked as invalidate it will
read from the DB and then it will
ultimately update the cache
again okay so this is how internally
update logic is written so this is very
important like uh sometimes during roll
back see most of always one thing is the
cash is sometimes it's a best effort
call Best
effort some sometime you are able trying
to write it but
fails you are trying to update it but
fails so we should not fail the
transaction itself man transactions are
very expensive right we should not fail
the transaction itself that okay my DB
is also updated everything is done
properly but I'm not able to update the
cash so let me fail the transaction no
so that's why sometime cash are best
effort so now here generally when you
invalidate the cash and let's say even
if the commit happened properly now you
are updating the cash if some failure
happened during
update okay and it will release the
law then also it's not an issue because
you have already marked as invalidate if
it is not update properly happen any
future call happen get call it see the
invalidate it will do a fresh read from
DB and later on override the cash data
properly
so that's why read write is more you can
say that generally in kind of a payment
industry this is more frequently
used so this is one example you can see
that uh I am doing first post insert
insert happen directly inserted into DB
then I made a get call you know that
during a get call Cash Miss will happen
it will make a DB call and then it will
insert into the cache load data into the
cache
now you are making a put call when you
are making a put call what you do is you
will put a lock
first you will put a invalidate then you
will hit the DB and after that you will
release the lock uh releasing lock and
all are not printing but after that you
know that it will update the cache also
with the latest data and release the log
and now when you doing last get call
Cash has the updated data right
so cash hit will
happen because updation happened
properly and then release loog
happened
okay then the second cat concurrency is
nonstrict rri this is you can say that
little bit lenient than read right
during read no lock is acquired at all
right during read it do not even check
whether there is a lock or not it
directly go ahead and try to read
it during
update after transaction commit
successfully cash is marked invalidate
and no update will with the fresh data
so consider this one in this scenario it
is little bit so the here the purpose of
nonstrict is that
uh try to put a lock for the less time
okay so that's where like for read it
remove the lock at all for update during
update what happen is transaction begin
then it will not uh acquire or it
will acquire lock on
cash it will not do any update or you
can uh invalidate the cash no cash is
not invalidate okay and then you can say
that it goes ahead and update
DB okay and after that if transaction
commit success
then it
will invalidate the
cash invalidate the cash and then
release the
lock okay so now here if you see that if
any
transaction roll back
happen if roll back
happen it won't do anything it won't
even inv validate thing it will just
release it
simply
right because uh data is not even like
up it is not even updating the cach
itself so that is not even
there so that's what good for heavy read
application so if update and read
happens in parallel it's a chance that
read operation might get EST stale data
because read is not acquiring lock lock
at all and while update is happening if
read also comes in parallel
maybe during update it might have it
might have updated the
DB okay but since read is not uh wait
for any log and everything and if it
read the data from the cach okay before
this
invalidated it will get the stale data
but it's a very small window but there
is a chance here in the at theate cach I
have put non District read right okay
and also let me put one debuger point in
J we know that the factory which we are
using is jcash region Factory which is
present into hibernate hibernate hyphen
cach so while doing application in
startup it will create a cache and then
ultimately it will goes to we have the
only one provider so this it will goes
to this provider right eh
cach and then we'll see that like I
starting the server so during
application startup
server jcash region Factory got invoked
right so now it takes care of creating
the cash and everything this Factory
okay it will take care of like creating
a cache
object
okay and uh invoking a proper API of
the uh you can say that the
jcash API interface which eventually
implemented by the your cash provider so
in that case uh here if you see
that this is the interface which is
coming from Cash Cash hyph API right
this is the interface and eh cach
manager is providing the implementation
okay so
once our server is started now let's
perform it first let's
do Post call so post uh so post call is
Success now let's see the DB what's the
data is stored in the
DB we have a data okay now and here also
we will check it like insert call is
made
so now we are trying to make a get call
in the get
call get call is Success we got the data
here if you see it make a select
query so first one is insert second one
is Select
and
now in the non strict read write what we
are saying is when you do a put call now
I am changing from now I am changing the
data from SJ to let's say SJ
updated if I run
this data is changed in the DB let's say
that it's Chang SJ
updated but what would happen have
happened internally inside the cash so
since transaction is committed
properly it has updated
properly it has also updated the cach
invalidated in cash it is not has the
latest data it didn't update SD updated
only it marked as invalided okay now if
I do a get call
I am able to get SG updated properly is
it coming from cash or new select query
would be made here if you see that a new
select query is made after update
because update only marked invalidate it
will
not update the cache
itself but if we change this to R
write read write
so if you change it to R write we can
see that uh the we can uh double test
the same behavior I am running the
insert during insert we will see an
insert call then during get call we will
see
a cach miss and then a select query now
it has inserted into the cache then
during put call it has first marked as
invalidated then update the DV after the
success transaction success also have
updated the cash also so update happen
after that if I do a get call Will I
getting a updated data yes so is it from
DB or cash there would not be any select
query cash
hit
okay so in the read
write it also update the cash but in the
non-strict it don't update the cash it
just make it invalidate
and the last one is
transactional in the transaction is you
can say that it's uh more restrict so it
acquire read log and also write
LW update the cash to after transaction
commit successfully similar to read
undor WR like once the transaction comit
successfully it update the cach
properly any other read operation during
cash log goes directly to DB what does
it mean I have an L2 cach
you have a DB if you have put in a
transactional uh cash currency now get
call is there let's say it has entity
one entity one so it put a log even
though it put a log and now if any get
call come it will say that it is locked
so get will try to fetch from the
DB okay and return so in this during
read also it act it act like like
a hard log where no other get call is
also even allowed to read from the L2
cach go and directly read from the DB if
any other right operation comes it has
to wait in Q okay till the cach uh till
the get log is not
released okay you can test it like uh
the way we have tested this read write
and uh nonstrict you can test with this
also so debug is a very helpful tool to
uh build this understanding so you can
do debug this one